Guide to the Rice University KTRU Radio records, 1962-2018 UA 011
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series I: Audio recordings, 1968-2007, 59004
  - Sub-Series: 1994/1995
    - The Last Wish live, 1995; wrc08126 (Box 24)
      Contents include: The Last Wish live, location unknown. Speakers: Justin Furstenfeld, Amy Immel, Katie Hartzog, Michelle Trautwein, Greg Hammond, Leital Molad, Brady Hammond, Abraham Diaz
  - Sub-Series: 1995/1996
    - Amy Denio live, 1995-09-06; wrc08141 (Box 24)
      Contents include: Amy Denio live at Hamman Hall. Speaker: Amy Denio
    - Amy Denio interview, 1995-09-16; wrc08138 (Box 24)
      Contents include: A KTRU DJ talks with Amy Denion about working with Japanese musicians, musical influences, The Billy Tipton Memorial Saxophone Quintet, and Muzak. She does a station ID. Speaker: Amy Denio
    - Bret Easton Ellis interview, 1995-09-18; wrc07969 (Box 24)
      Contents include: (00:01) A KTRU DJ interviews Bret Easton Ellis about his book "The Informers," his focus on the 1980s, morality of his work, reviews, writing ideas, the culture wars, his optioned books, research, his early career, influences, how he fits in the writing world, writing for Generation X, being apolitical, drugs, "Kids," and current writing. Recording ends abruptly. There are two other shows on this reel: Deep Thoughts and Open Line, which are noted in Sub-Series T: 1994/1995. Speakers: Bret Easton Ellis
    - KTRU News Show - Criss/Cross Consultants, 1995-10-11; wrc07981 (Box 24)
      Contents include: On "KTRU News Show," Katherine Claire of Criss/Cross Consultants talks about her work with the cross dressing community to provide private consultations including purchasing clothing, and advice for make-up, hair, and dress. She defines cross dressers as heterosexual males who want to dress as woman, but not become women. She does not serve the transvestite, transgender, or drag queen communities. She discusses motivations for cross dressers using her service, repressing femininity, shopping, how she started in the business, Halloween activities, looking to purchase a store front, and upcoming film "Creating Carolyn." We deleted music and another program at the end of this recording. Speakers: Katherine Claire, Jeffrey Rios
    - Flap - Homi Bhabha, 1995-10-23; wrc07970 (Box 24)
      Contents include: On "Flap," Shaila Dewan talks to Homi Bhabha about Salman Rushdi, performance art, the politics of exile, and his early life. Lisa Czyszczewski talks about mediocrity. Jenny Salomon, Homi Bhabha, Lisa Czyszczewski
    - Flap - Minnie Bruce Pratt, 1995-10-30; wrc08134 (Box 24)
      Contents include: On "Flap," Shaila Dewan talks to Minnie Bruce Pratt about butch/femme, gender expression, traditional roles, her childhood, her mother, writing, and losing custody of her children based on her sexuality. In between the interview, Rangi McNeil reads a poem. Speakers: Minnie Bruce Pratt, Shaila Dewan, Rangi McNeil
    - Spoken Word - Jess De Witt, 1995-11-03; wrc08133 (Box 24)
      Contents include: On "Spoken Word," Jess De Witt talks about performing, pleasure, reads poetry, and plays music. Speaker: Jess De Witt
    - Flap - Might Magazine, 1995; wrc07982 (Box 24)
      Contents include: On "Flap," Jenny Salomon interviews Paul Tullis and Zev Borrow of "Might Magazine" about how they came to "Might," the Jack in the Box article, favorite articles, goals of the magazine, Texas arrest, humor, Christian Science Monitor, cheesy stuff, O.J. verdict, magazine's finances, and impressions. Speakers: Shaila Dewan, Jenny Salomon, Paul Tullis, Zev Borrow
    - Silkworm live, 1995; wrc08137 (Box 24)
      Contents include: Silkworm live, location unknown. Speakers: Tim Midgett, Michael Dahlquist, Andy Cohen
    - Tibetan Monks, 1996-04-22; wrc08139 (Box 24)
      Contents include: Tibetan Monks perform live at KTRU.
    - KTRU Outdoor Show 1, 1996-04; wrc08140 (Box 24)
      Contents include: (00:01) Ultra Hummus live. (10:46) Project Grimm live. (01:00:02) Jessica 6 live. We removed radio music between sets. Speakers: John Cramer, Rick Costello, Drew Calhoun, Jim Otterson, Ramon Medina
    - KTRU Outdoor Show 3, 1996-04; wrc08136 (Box 24)
      Contents include: (00:01) Tim Berne's Bloodcount live. (37:00) Unknown band, electronica. (51:30) Bad Ass. Speakers: Tim Berne, Herb Robertson, Joey Baron, David Sanborn, Kathy McCarty, Chris Nelson, John Paul
    - Sincola live, 1996-06-22; wrc08135 (Box 24)
      Contents include: Sincola live, location unknown. Speakers: Wendel Stivers, Kris Patterson, Chepo Pena, Terri Lord, Rebecca Cannon
  - Sub-Series: 1996/1997
    - Erin Yownt and Personality Crisis live, 1996-08-27; wrc08143 (Box 24)
      Contents include: (00:01) Erin Yownt [?] live at KTRU. (26:00) Personality Crisis. Speakers: Willie Dunivan, Robin Geiger
    - KTRU Outdoor Show, 1997-03-22; wrc08142 (Box 24)
      Contents include: (00:01) Spoon live; (27:08) Texas Guinness Lovers live; (01:13:54) Sarge live. Speakers: Britt Daniel, Josh Zarbo, Jim Eno, Brad Shenfeld, Kilian Sweeney, Phil Gayle, Bill Savoie, Jennifer Neira, Chris Bakos, Bo Morrison, Elizabeth Elmore, Rachel Switzky
    - Bowery Electric live, 1997; wrc08146 (Box 24)
      Contents include: A KTRU DJ talks to Bowery Electric about their new album Beat, touring, future plans, rehearsal space, playing in New York, and Factory Press. They perform live at KTRU. Speakers: Lawrence Chandler, Martha Schwendener, Wayme Magruder
    - Donkey live, 1997; wrc08145 (Box 24)
      Contents include: Donkey live, a band from Amsterdam, location unknown.
    - Finn Taylor interview, 1997; wrc08144 (Box 24)
      Contents include: A KTRU DJ talks to Finn Taylor about this new movie "Dream with the Fishes," Sundance Film Festival, directing for the first time, re-writing his screenplays, movie soundtrack. Speakers: Finn Taylor
    - Richard Cagle and Randall Jamail interview, 1997; wrc08147 (Box 24)
      Contents include: A KTRU DJ talks to Richard Cagle and Randall Jamail of the Artist Management Group about musical talent in Houston, promotion issues, collaboration, a good band, why bands need a manager, why bands might need a label, the Hellhole Compilation, controversy surrounding the compilation, Justice Records, and new recordings. Speakers: Richard Cagle, Randall Jamail
  - Sub-Series: 1997/1998
    - Helium live, 1997-11-18; wrc08149 (Box 24)
      Contents include: Helium live, location unknown. They also talk about touring, how Ash Bowie has changed the sound, favorite candy, song meaning, and answer silly questions. Speakers: Mary Lou Lord, Brian Dunton, Mary Timony, Ash Bowie, Shawn Devlin
    - KTRU Outdoor Show 1, 1998-04-04; wrc08150 (Box 24)
      Contents include: (00:01) Phil Gayle Trio live. (49:55) Secret Agent 8 live. (01:30:12) Wholesome Rollers live. Speakers: Dave Dove, Phil Gayle, Will Frith, Zack Clayton, Kenny Dickman, Clint Dale, Aaron Koerner, David Evans, Chris Jensen, Justin Brouillard
    - KTRU Outdoor Show 2, 1998-04-04; wrc08151 (Box 24)
      Contents include: (00:01) Slight Surface Noise [?] live. (24:55) Little Jack Melody and His Young Turks live. (01:23:53) Bruce Eisenbeil Trio live. Speakers: Bruce Eisenbeil, Lou Grassi, Rob Brown, Adolfo Acosta, Jim Cocke, Aaron Crouch, Dave Dorbin, Jacob Duncan, Terry Hankins, Little Jack Melody, Chad Makela, Jerome Rossen, Joe Shyka, David Wilcox, Mike Switzer, Vaughan Boone
    - KTRU Outdoor Show 3, 1998-04-04; wrc08148 (Box 24)
      Contents include: John Fahey live at the KTRU Outdoor Show. Speaker: John Fahey
  - Sub-Series: 1998/1999
    - Gomez interview, 1998-10; wrc08152 (Box 24)
      Contents include: KTRU DJ interviews Gomez about their Mercury Prize, blues influences, Ben Harper, other genre influences, Massive Attack, Santana, touring, history, writing new music, favorite cereal, breakfast, groupies, and travelling. Speakers: Tom Gray, Paul Blackburn
    - Westbury Squares live, 1999-04-10; wrc08153 (Box 24)
      Contents include: Westbury Squares live at the KTRU Outdoor Show. Speakers: Mickey DeLeon, Davey McEathron, Vince Hernandez
    - Brown Whörnet live, 1999-04-10; wrc08154 (Box 24)
      Contents incude: Brown Whörnet live at the KTRU Outdoor Show. Speakers: Anti-Ear, Carolyn Cremona, Clay Embry, Jimmy Burdine, Julien Peterson, Peter Stopschinski
    - Freedom Sold live, 1999-04-10; wrc08155 (Box 24)
      Contents include: Freedom Sold live at the KTRU Outdoor Show. Speakers: Kwame Anderson, Arthur Salazar
    - Spaceheads live, 1999-06-04; wrc08156 (Box 24)
      Contents include: Spacheads live, location unknown. Speakers: Andy Diagram, Richard Harrison
  - Sub-Series: 1999/2000
    - Buddies live, 1999-10-29; wrc08158 (Box 24)
      Contents include: Buddies live, location unknown. The audio is quite poor quality.
    - Death Penalty Debate, 1999-11-09; wrc08160 (Box 24)
      Contents include: Death Penalty Debate featuring Mandy Welch and Dr. Baruch Brody. The debate took place during Rice Amnesty International's Death Penalty Awareness Week. Speakers: Baruch Brody, Mandy Welch
    - Bobby Conn live, 1999-12-11; wrc08159 (Box 24)
      Contents include: Bobby Conn live, location unknown. He also does an interview. A KTRU DJ talks to him about Llovesonngs, Nilsson Schmilsson, touring, and his upcoming show. Speakers: Bobby Conn
    - Mike Rosenthal live, 1999; wrc08157 (Box 24)
      Contents include: (00:00) Mike Rosenthal live; (32:56) Carter Brown live. Speakers: Mike Rosenthal, Justin Crane, Carter Brown
  - Sub-Series: 2000/2001
    - KTRU Outdoor Show, 2001-04-14; wrc08161 (Box 24)
      Contents include: (00:01) Dennis Gonzalez Yells at Eels live. (04:38) Quintron and Miss Pussycat live. (43:08) The Deathray Davies live. (01:27:35) Lozenge We deleted radio music between sets. Speakers: Tim Green, Aaron Gonzalez, Stefan Gonzalez, Dennis Gonzalez, John Dufilho, Jason Garner, Bill Shupp, Lindsay Romig, Kevin Ingle, Kurt Johnson, Kyle Bruckmann, Mark Stevens, Philip Montoro
    - KTRU Outdoor Show, 2001-04-14; wrc08162 (Box 24)
      Contents include: (00:01) Matty and Mossy live [?] (15:10) 25 Suaves live. (29:20) Philip Gelb live. (01:05:00) Dennis Gonzalez Yells at Eels live. We deleted radio music between sets. Speakers: Peter Larson, Fumie Kawasaki, Tim Green, Aaron Gonzalez, Stefan Gonzalez, Dennis Gonzalez, Heath Flagtvedt, John Hunter, Shoko Hikage, Tim Perkis
    - KTRU Outdoor Show, 2001-04-14; wrc08163 (Box 24)
      Contents include: (00:01) Lozenge live (17:02) The Rondelles live. Speakers: Kurt Johnson, Kyle Bruckmann, Mark Stevens, Philip Montoro, Cory Shane, Juliet Swango, Oakley Munson, Yukiko Moynihan
    - My Education live, 2001; wrc08164 (Box 24)
      Contents include: My Education live at KTRU. Speakers: Sean Seagler, Eric Gibbons, Brian Purington, Chris Hackstie, Kirk Laktas, James Alexander, Travis Weller
  - Sub-Series: 2001/2002
    - Elizabeth Elmore live, 2001-11-17; wrc08165 (Box 25)
      Contents include: Elizabeth Elmore plays live at KTRU. She also talks to KTRU DJs about law school, her show in Lyle's, Speaker: Elizabeth Elmore, Chad Romanski, Greg Mytych, Joel Root, Scott Rosenquist, Sean Hulet
  - Sub-Series: 2002/2003
    - Susan Alcorn live, 2003-04-13; wrc08166 (Box 25)
      Contents include: Susan Alcorn live at the KTRU Outdoor Show. Speaker: Susan Alcorn
    - The Fighting Type and Rotten Piece live, 2003-04-13; wrc08167 (Box 25)
      Contents include: (00:01) The Fighting Type live. (13:14) Rotten Piece live. Both are playing at the KTRU Outdoor Show. Sections of this recording during The Fighting Type set may have degraded on the original DAT tape. We deleted dead air throughout the recording. Speakers: Lance Walker, Carol Sandin, Shaun Kelly
  - Sub-Series: 2003/2004
    - The New Sound of My Bossa Nova live, 2004-04-17; wrc08168 (Box 25)
      Contents include: The New Sound of My Bossa Nova live at the KTRU Outdoor Show. Speakers: Justin Shay, Patrick Elkins, Kelly Szott, Jason Voss
    - Jana Hunter live, 2004-04-17; wrc08169 (Box 25)
      Contents include: Jana Hunter live at the KTRU Outdoor Show. Speaker: Jana Hunter
    - Muzak live, 2004-04-17; wrc08170 (Box 25)
      Contents include: Muzak live at the KTRU Outdoor Show. Speaker: Johnny Muzak
    - KTRU Outdoor Show, 2004-04-17; wrc08171 (Box 25)
      Contents include: Telephone Company live. (26:28) Weird Weeds live. (53:23) Rua Minx live. Speakers: Sandy Ewen, Nick Hennies, Aaron Russell, Lindsay Verrill, Donna Huanca
  - Sub-Series: 2004/2005
    - Anna Oxygen live, 2005-04-03; wrc08172 (Box 25)
      Contents include: Anna Oxygen performs live at the KTRU Outdoor Show. Speakers: Anna Jordan Huff, Anna Oxygen
    - Dave Dove and Tree Wave live, 2005-04-03; wrc08173 (Box 25)
      Contents include: (00:01) Dave Dove live at the KTRU Outdoor Show. (25:01) Tree Wave live at the KTRU Outdoor Show. We deleted radio music in between sets. Speakers: Dave Dove, Paul Slocum, Lauren Gray
  - Sub-Series: 2005/2006
    - My Education live, 2005-08-28; wrc08174 (Box 25)
      Contens include: My Education live in the KTRU studios. Speakers: Travis Weller, James Alexander, Brian Purington, Chris Hackstie, Eric Gibbons, Sean Ziegler, Kirk Laktas
    - ADULT Station IDs, 2005-11-04; wrc08010 (Box 25)
      Contents include: Adam Lee Miller and Nicola Kuperus do station IDs. Speakers: Adam Lee Miller, Nicola Kuperus
    - Found Magazine interview, 2005; wrc08011 (Box 25)
      Contents include: A KTRU DJ talks to Davy Rothbart of Found Magazine about what the magazine does, touring, "Dirty Found," stories about the found items, and "The Lone Surfer of Montana, Kansas." He does a station ID. Speakers: Davy Rothbart
    - KTRU Outdoor Show, 2006-04-29; wrc08175 (Box 25)
      Contents include: (00:01) The Old-Timerz live. (30:18) Satin Hooks live. (51:37) Go Spread Your Wings live. (01:15:31) Sam Prekop live. We deleted dead air and radio music between sets. Speakers: Patrick Healy, Kenny Melonson, Lucas Gorham, David Gomez, Sam Prekop
  - Sub-Series: 2006/2007
    - KTRU Outdoor Show, 2007-04-07; wrc08176 (Box 25)
      Contents include: (00:01) Despot live (23:10) 120 Days live. Sections of this recording during 120 Days set may have degraded on the original DAT tape. We removed sections with no sound and radio music in the middle and end. Speakers: Alex Resinsetin, Despot, Ådne Meisfjord, Kjetil Ovesen, Jonas Hestvik Dahl, Arne Kvalvik
    - KTRU Outdoor Show, 2007-04-07; wrc08177 (Box 25)
      Contents include: (00:01) Moxie live (42:43) The Dimes live. We removed sections with no sound and radio music in the middle. Speakers: Johnny Clay, Pierre Johnson, Ryan Johnston
- Series II: Administrative files, programming, and correspondence, 1968-1989, 59005
  - Administrative Files, 59778
    - KTRU Elections, 1970s-1980s; 59739 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Director's meeting minutes, 1981-1982; 59742 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - KTRU staff meeting minutes, 1983-1985; 59743 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Committee meetings and proposals, 1970s-1980s; 59777 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Federal Communications Commission forms (KTRU Hardware Specifics), 1970s; 59772 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Federal Communications Commission radio operator permits, 1970s-1980s; 59773 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Orders from Record companies, 1976; 59765 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Business and money: Receipts, warranties, blueprints, etc., 1970s-1980s; 59780 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - KTRU flood damage reports and expenses, 1976; 59761 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Department transactions, 1976; 59763 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Newsclippings and related papers
    - KTRU information packet, 2002-2003; 59776 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - KTRU news and memorandums, 1970s-1980s; 59755 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Newsclippings about KTRU, 1970s-1980s; 59756 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Newsclippings about music trends, other stations, related topics, 1980-1984; 59757 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Collected finances, distribution network, news, notes, business cards, 1968-70; 59781 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Visual Aids, 59770 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Flyers, 1980s-2010s; 174992 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - 50 years of KTRU book and bumper sticker, 59775 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Station Programming Documents, 59768
    - Master programming log, 1981; 59741 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Instructions and Documents for running the KTRU station, 1970s-1980s; 59759 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - DJ Manuals, 1979, 1997; 174993 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - DJ schedules and staff lists, 1980s; 59740 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Playlists and Folios, 1970s, 1980s; 59760 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Rice event programs and speeches, 1969-1970s; 59769 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Newsmaster notes for program, 1970; 59744 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Overplayed songs, 59767 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Contests, 1980s; 59754 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - The Elmo (prank caller) Chart, n.d., 59745 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 59764
    - Listeners' correspondence, 1970s-1980s (part 1/2); 59753 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Listeners' correspondence, 1970s-1980s (part 2/2); 59766 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - KTRUer (staff) correspondence, 1970-1983; 59752 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - RMC and KTRU correspondence, 1970s-1980s; 59774 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Questionnaires and ascertainments, 1970s-1980s; 59779 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - KTRU Culture, 59758
    - KTRU Groans and Gripes, 1976-77; 59746 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - KTRU Groans and Gripes, 1981; 59747 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - KTRU Groans and Gripes, 1982-83; 59748 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - KTRU Groans and Gripes, 1984-85; 59749 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - KTRU Groans and Gripes, 1986; 59750 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - KTRU Groans and Gripes, 1987; 59751 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - KTRU staff internal banter, 1970s-1980s; 59771 (Box 27, Folder 18)
- Series III: Oversized Materials, 2010, 160597
  - Save KTRU poster, 2010; 160598 (Map-drawer 148, Item 3)
    General Note
    Rice University Architectural drawings, oversize manuscript material, maps and photographs, Part 3 of 3 (UA 226-3)
- Series IV: Addendum
  - Correspondence, 1994-2010 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Fliers, 2013-2018; n.d. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Folio / Noize Letter, 2008; 2018 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 1990s-2010s (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Newsclippings regarding sale of KTRU to UH, from UH newspaper, 2010 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Jandek performing at 50th anniversary concert, 2017-2018
    Contents include: pdfs and and a jpg of contracts, emails, and other information related to the 50th anniversary concert featuring Jandek, Open Mike Eagle, Austin Sepulvado, and Peter Silberman